<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indistinguishability Analysis on Jan Richter-Brockmann</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/indistinguishability-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indistinguishability Analysis on Jan Richter-Brockmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/indistinguishability-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>INDIANA - Verifying (Random) Probing Security through Indistinguishability Analysis.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/indiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/indiana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While masking is a widely used defense against passive side-&#xA;channel attacks, its secure implementation in hardware continues to be&#xA;a manual, complex, and error-prone process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces INDIANA, a comprehensive security verification&#xA;methodology for hardware masking. Our results include a hardware verification tool, enabling a complete analysis of simulation-based security in&#xA;the glitch-extended probing model and intra-cycle estimations for leak-&#xA;age probabilities in the random probing model. Notably, INDIANA is the&#xA;first framework to analyze arbitrary masked circuits in both models, even&#xA;at the scale of full SPN cipher rounds (e.g., AES), while delivering exact&#xA;verification results. To achieve accurate and comprehensive verification,&#xA;we propose a partitionable probing distinguisher that allows for fast vali-&#xA;dation of probe tuples, surpassing current methods that rely on statistical&#xA;independence. Furthermore, our approach naturally supports extensions&#xA;to the random probing model by utilizing Fast Fourier-Hadamard Trans-&#xA;formations (FHTs).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
